Connor Secen

Machine Learning Research Engineer

For the past seven years, I have held hardware and software positions. From these positions, I have learned how to work in team settings to reach a common goal. These experiences have provided me with the knowledge I need to be an effective software developer.

WORK EXPERIENCE

2022-06 – Machine Learning Research Engineer present Leidos

- Maintained and improved existing ConvLSTM model as lead machine learning developer on the program
- Performed thorough data analysis on real data to aid with the validation of ML models and to help improve the data synthesis process
- Lead the development of a transformer model as an alternative model to the ConvLSTM
- Lead the development of a data generator and rest API in Python to demonstrate the ability of existing MATLAB application

2019-07 - **Software Developer**

2022-06 Leidos

- Facilitated transfer of data from multiple sources in different formats to JIRA/Confluence by writing Python script to automate the process
- Upgraded and tested multiple Visual Basic 6 applications to the more modern .NET 2019
- Reduced diagnostic time in JIRA by writing analysis script to analyze log data in Python
- Simplified SLOC counting process runtime by refactoring original script to automate more of the process and increase efficiency in the code

2017-01 – Data Science Intern

2019-07

ICG Solutions

- Increased data collection efficiency by co-writing Python application to automate the process of scraping user profile information from Twitter
- Performed ad hoc testing during multiple releases of commercial software helping to reduce bugs and prepare for launch
- Assessed data analytics software and developed training guides for various end user skill levels, including first time users, intermediate level users, and administrators

PERSONAL PROJECTS

- Surf Forecasting Dashboard: Display forecasted data collected from scraping web
 pages in an easily digestible web dashboard. Technologies used: Python 3, Plotly Dash
 Jupyter Labs
- WSL Wave Score Analysis: Conduct analysis on wave scores and counts from the last 3
 years of professional surfing events. Technologies used: Python, Seaborn, Pandas,
 Jupyter Notebooks
- **Sudoku Solver:** Use a custom-built genetic algorithm to solve any size sudoku board. *Technologies used: Numpy, Python 3, Jupyter Notebook*
- Machine Learning Research: Worked alongside machine learning professor to develop a model to predict mechanical functions. *Technologies used: Python 3, Tensorflow*

INTERPERSONAL EXPERIENCE

- Alpine ski instructor for beginner to intermediate level skiers
- Organized and managed a group of 30 people to assemble and install information kiosk to earn Eagle Scout

Personal Info

E-mail

secen.0609@gmail.com

GitHub

github.com/csecen

LinkedIn

linkedin.com/in/connor-secen

Website

csecen.github.io

Skills

Python, Java ••••

Advanced

Jupyter Labs

Advanced

Pydata Stack

Advanced

AWS

OOOO Moderate

GIT

00000

Moderate

Certifications/Awards

AWS Certified Developer – Associate 2018-08 – 2020-08

Coursera Deep Learning Certificate 2020-06

Eagle Scout

2011-09

Education

Drexel University, Philadelphia, PA M.S. in Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning 2024

University of Maryland, College Park, MD

B.S. in Computer Science 2019

Graduate Courses

Machine Learning
Deep Learning
Applied Artificial Intelligence
Quantitative Data Science